A new kind of enemy. A new kind of war.
Starship Troopers is a adventure, action, thriller
film directed by Paul Verhoeven.
Set in the future, the story follows a young soldier named
Johnny Rico and his exploits in the Mobile Infantry.
Rico's military career progresses from recruit to non-commissioned officer and finally to officer against the
backdrop of an interstellar war between mankind and an arachnoid species known as "the Bugs."
Johnny D. Rico, played by Casper Van Dien.
Dizzy Flores, played by Dina Meyer.
Carmen Ibañez, played by Denise Richards.
Private Ace Levy, played by Jake Busey.
Colonel Carl Jenkins, played by Neil Patrick Harris.
Career Sergeant Zim, played by Clancy Brown.
Starship Troopers is a 1997 American science fiction action film directed by Paul
Verhoeven and written by Edward Neumeier, based on the 1959 novel by Robert A.
Set in the 23rd century, the story follows teenager Johnny Rico and his comrades as they serve in the military of the United Citizen
Federation, an Earth-based world government engaged in an interstellar war against an alien species known as the Arachnids.
The film stars Casper Van Dien, Dina Meyer, Denise Richards, Jake Busey,
Neil Patrick Harris, Patrick Muldoon, and Michael Ironside.
Development of Starship Troopers began in 1991 as Bug
Hunt at Outpost 7, written by Neumeier.
After recognizing similarities between Neumeier's script and Heinlein's book, producer Jon Davison suggested
aligning the script more closely with the novel to garner greater interest from studio executives.
Despite these efforts development was slow, with studios hesitant to
fund the costly project right up to the start of filming.
Principal photography took place between April and October 1996 on a $100–110 million budget, of which nearly half was spent on
the extensive computer-generated imagery (CGI) and practical effects required to vivify the Arachnid creatures.
Released on November 7, 1997, Starship Troopers faced critical backlash, with reviewers interpreting
the film as endorsing fascism and disparaging its violence and cast performances.
Despite initial box office success, collections slowed down amid negative reviews and unfavorable word of mouth,
culminating in a $121 million total gross against its budget, which made it the 34th-highest-grossing film of 1997.
The disappointing performance of Starship Troopers was blamed, in part, on competition from a high number of successful or anticipated science fiction
and genre films released that year, its satire and violence failing to connect with mainstream audiences, and ineffective marketing.
Since its release, Starship Troopers has been critically re-evaluated, and it is now considered a cult classic
and a prescient satire of fascism and authoritarian governance that has grown in relevance.
The film launched a multimedia franchise that includes four sequels—Starship Troopers 2: Hero of the Federation (2004), Starship Troopers 3: Marauder (2008), Starship Troopers:
Invasion (2012), and Starship Troopers: Traitor of Mars (2017)—as well as a 1999 animated television series, video games, comics, and a variety of merchandise.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, space marine,
army, moon, based on novel or book.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.